BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

CLOUD DEVOPS ENGINEER - SINGAPORE AIRLINES. SINGAPORE

ONLINE

http://bharathkumaraju.com

in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraju

CONTACT BIO DETAILS
Singapore DOB: 12-June-1987

t: +49 15226684839 Passport: J7879295





SUMMARY:

Over 8 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Aviation, Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, **automation**, **continuous deployment(CICD)** pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Puppet, Git, Bamboo, Vagrant, Docker, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetbeat.

Monitoring/Log Sysdig, Newrelic, Datadog, AppDynamics, Sumologic, sensu, flapjack, Grafana, graphite.

Programming Python, Shell Scripting, Java. RDBMS Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu, Coreos, Redhat Atomic

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications AWS Solution Architect and VMware Cloud Professional

EXPERIENCE:

Singapore Airlines,

Singapore (Mar 2019-Present) Automated AWS Cloud deployments and builds using the Jenkinsfile. Implemented automated Stack deployments using Cloud Formation. Working on openshift container platform to move legacy apps to k8s.

Delivion GmBH, Essen,Germany Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs. Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications.

(Mar 2018-Mar 2019) Wo

Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps.

Standard Chartered, Chennai, India Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic

(Oct 2016-Mar 2018) Stack.

Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution.

 $Worked \ on \ Micro-service \ Architecture \ with \ spring \ config \ server \ for \ dynamic \ variable \ substitution \ in \ ansible.$

Trimble Navigation,

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

Chennai, India

 $Created\ Development,\ QA,\ Stage,\ Production\ stacks\ \&\ maintaining\ them\ securely\ using\ robust\ VPC\ design.$

(Jun2014-Sep2016) Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment.

Hewlett-Packard, Chennai, India (Mar2011-May2014) Performing Software installation, upgrade/patches, troubleshooting & maintenance on UNIX Servers. Administered DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automating the deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX.

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

BSC- Graduation Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

(Jul2004-May2007) Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

INTERESTS:

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.